<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>images on PageDart</title>
    <link>https://pagedart.com/categories/images/</link>
    <description>Recent content in images on PageDart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pagedart.com/categories/images/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Optimize Images for Websites: Without Losing Quality</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-optimize-images-for-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-optimize-images-for-websites/</guid>
      <description>People of the internet, you&#39;re obsessed with cats.
One of the most famous internet cats is Grumpy Cat on Instagram.
He has over 2.7 million followers. 2.7 million!
There is a problem with this. These cats are slowing down the internet.
  Well, the cats are not slowing down the internet. Pictures are slowing down the internet.
These images are getting bigger in file size. Which means they are slowing down webpages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Alt Text SEO Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/image-alt-text-seo-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/image-alt-text-seo-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Let&#39;s look at the SEO best practices for setting image alt text.
You must remember that the reason you use alt text is to describe the image to visually impaired users.
Never forget this.
Whenever you are writing your alt text descriptions you should always have this in mind.
Alt text is for humans not for you to get better rankings.
Yet, the trick is to give an excellent description that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linking Image in HTML: How to create links from images</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/linking-images-in-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/linking-images-in-html/</guid>
      <description>We are going to take a beginner friendly look at how to create image links on your website.
We will look at which HTML tags you need to use in the code.
If you have never done this before, don&#39;t worry! I will guide you through the whole process.
By the end of this article, you will be creating image links all over your web page and the Internet.
We are also going to look at some more advanced techniques towards the end of the article if you are feeling brave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimize Images for Page Speed</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/optimize-images-for-page-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/optimize-images-for-page-speed/</guid>
      <description>One thing is clear we have to learn how to optimize images for the web.
Images are getting bigger and this affects user experience.
According to reports from HTTP Archive images account for over 60% of your website.
HTTP Archive also tracks image size in 2010 the average size was 225kb and in 2019 we are now up to under a meg.
While the number of image requests has gone down in that same period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Lazy Loading?</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/what-is-lazy-loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/what-is-lazy-loading/</guid>
      <description>Lazy loading is a way of making your site faster.
We will look at three things:
 What is lazy loading? Why should I add lazy loading to my site? How do I add lazy loading to my site?  Lazy loading can have a huge impact on your website speed. If you have many images or youtube videos on a page this technique can speed things up.
And it’s easier to set up than you would think.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>