<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>search on PageDart</title>
    <link>https://pagedart.com/categories/search/</link>
    <description>Recent content in search on PageDart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 18:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pagedart.com/categories/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Google Search to a Website</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/add-google-search-to-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 18:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/add-google-search-to-a-website/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we are going to cover the fastest way to add Google Search to a website.
I will show you a super quick way to add a Google search box on your website in under 5 minutes.
Some of you who land on this page may not be looking to add a Google search box on your site.
You may be looking to get your website pages into the Google search results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add a Search Bar in HTML</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-add-a-search-bar-in-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 12:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-add-a-search-bar-in-html/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we are going to add a search bar in HTML to your site!
I will walk you through all the components you need to add a search bar in HTML and connect it to Google to search.
Google will open in a new tab and only show results for your site.
For those in a rush, the complete solution is at the bottom of the page. For those who want the deep dive keep reading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Search to WordPress Menu</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/add-search-to-wordpress-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/add-search-to-wordpress-menu/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we are going to add search to the WordPress Menu.
This is not as easy as you might think!
There is no easy way in the WordPress admin area to add the search bar. But fear not, I will show you two ways you can add the search bar yourself.
One option will have you installing an off-the-shelf plugin. The second option is adding some code to your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Search for Custom Post Type</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/wordpress-search-for-custom-post-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/wordpress-search-for-custom-post-type/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we are going to create a search bar that will only search your custom post types in WordPress.
We will cover:
 How to Create a Custom Post Type  Adding a Custom Post Type with Code Using a plugin to create a Custom Post Type   Creating a Custom Post My Custom Post Type is not Showing in Search How to Search only a Custom Post Type WordPress Search for Custom Post Type, Final Thoughts   Let&#39;s dive in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a search index?</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/what-is-a-search-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/what-is-a-search-index/</guid>
      <description>We take search for granted today on the internet.
We use Google daily to find information across billions of pages in under a second.
Do we ever stop to think how magical this is? How does a search index work?
Today we are going to dive into search and what is a search index.
In this article we will cover:
 What is a search index? How are search indexes made?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>