<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on PageDart</title>
    <link>https://pagedart.com/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on PageDart</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pagedart.com/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install node.js, the easy way</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-install-node-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-install-node-js/</guid>
      <description>We are going to look at how to install node.js the easy way on Mac OS X, Windows and Linux.
You don&#39;t need to download the node package and try to install it. No! We are going to do it the easy way using package managers.
Once you have node installed you will be able to run server-side JavaScript on your computer.
We will also look at how you can upgrade node so you always have the latest version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to link JavaScript to HTML</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-link-javascript-to-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-link-javascript-to-html/</guid>
      <description>When creating web pages there comes a time when you need to do a bit more than display content. You need to load JavaScript.
One of the first JavaScript files added is Google Analytics to track page loads and visitors.
But how do you link JavaScript to HTML?
In this tutorial, we are going to cover how to link JavaScript to HTML. We will look at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Call a Function in JavaScript?</title>
      <link>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-call-a-function-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pagedart.com/blog/how-to-call-a-function-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Functions are one of the main building blocks for JavaScript development.
In this article we are going to look at:
 How to call a function in JavaScript How to call a function from HTML How to call a function using the onclick event handler How to create a self-invoking function How to call an arrow function  There is a lot to cover!
This is a beginner tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>